A Guide to the Papers of Rowland Egger, 1945-1971
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Rowland Egger 1945-1971
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
6850-d
This collection consists of ca. 100 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Scope and Content Information
This addition to the Rowland Egger papers spanning the years 1945-1971 consists of ca. 100 items. These papers contain mainly reports, memoranda, and letters received or produced by Egger while serving on the President's Task Force on Government Reorganization, July-November, 1964.
There are three letters from President Lyndon Baines Johnson to Egger thanking him for working on the Task Force and expressing appreciation for work done in Bolivia, prior to the organization of the Task Force.
Drafts drawn up by Egger and Donald K. Price, Chairman of the Task Force, were prepared to set a basis for discussion during the Task Force meetings. Also included are electrostatic copies of the revised and final drafts of the report of the President's Task Force on Government Reorganization.
There is an electrostatic copy of a press release from the Office of the White House Press Secretary dealing mainly about four major domestic problems: education, health, conservation of natural resources, and farm policy. Many of the problems stated in the press release were studied by the Task Force.
One article of interest in the collection not dealing with the President's Task Force was a memorandum submitted by President Richard M. Nixon's Advisory Council on Executive Organization on Natural Resources.
Contents List
- The Organization and Administration of the Department of State: Bureau of the Budget 1945 1945 Aug. 5 (Box 1)
- Electrostatic copy of article from the Georgetown Law Journal Cooperation or Conflict? by James Rowe, Jr. 1947 (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous reports, memoranda and letters 1959, 1964, n.d. (Box 1)
- Reports of Department of Natural Resources and Agriculture 1959, 1964, n.d. (Box 1)
- Reports on Executive Management of Presidential Office 1960-1962, 1964, n.d. (Box 1)
- Report on Reorganization Plan of Executive Development 1961, 1963 (Box 1)
- Reports on Bank Supervision 1962, 1964, 1966 (Box 1)
- Report of the Committee on Financial Institutions to the President of the United States 1963 April 1 (Box 1)
- TLS to Rowland Egger from President Lyndon Baines Johnson 1963, 1964 (Box 1)
- Reports on Foreign Affairs 1963, 1964 (Box 1)
- TLS concerning formation of Task Force on Government Reorganization 1964 July 17 & 20 (Box 1)
- Report on Discharge for Inefficiency and in Reduction-In-Force 1964 Aug. 24 (Box 1)
- Reports on Domestic Development 1964 Sept. 2 & Oct. 22 (Box 1)
- Reports on Federal Educational Activities 1964 Oct. 2 & 19 (Box 1)
- Report on Bureau of Narcotics 1964 Oct. 7 (Box 1)
- Draft by Rowland Egger for discussion by Task Force meeting of Oct. 23, 1964 1964 Oct. 16 (Box 1)
- Memorandum to Task Force on Government Reorganization by Donald K. Price 1964 Oct. 27 (Box 1)
- Release from the office of the White House Press Secretary 1964 Nov. 1 (Box 1)
- Draft of Task Force revisions of Nov. 5, 1964 1964 Nov. 5 (Box 1)
- Report of the President's Task Force on Government Reorganization 1964 Nov. 6, 2 folders (Box 1)
- Reports on Economics Development Programs 1964, n.d. (Box 1)
- Reports on the Reorganization Finance Corporation 1964 (Box 2)
- Report on Proposals to Improve the Higher Civil Service Comparative Analysis1964 (Box 2)
- Report on abolishing or transferring government agencies 1964 (Box 2)
- Reports on abolishing or transferring government agencies 1964 (Box 2)
- Reports on Housing and Community Development 1964, n.d. (Box 2)
- Reports on transportation planning 1964 (Box 2)
- Report on Legislative Encroachment on the President 1964 (Box 2)
- Memoranda on President Nixon's Advisory Council on Executive Organization 1971 (Box 2)
- Report on appointment and removal power in committees n.d. (Box 2)
- Task Force Government Organization Program n.d. (Box 2)